<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 22:21:05 -0500</pubDate><title><![CDATA[About]]></title><url><![CDATA[about]]></url><meta><![CDATA[]]></meta><metad><![CDATA[]]></metad><menu><![CDATA[About]]></menu><menuOrder><![CDATA[0]]></menuOrder><menuStatus><![CDATA[]]></menuStatus><template><![CDATA[template.php]]></template><parent><![CDATA[]]></parent><content><![CDATA[&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Reform Luach was compiled in consultation with many Reform sources, including Mark Washofsky&#039;s &lt;em&gt;Jewish Living&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Mishkan T&#039;filah&lt;/em&gt;, the Plaut Torah commentaries, &lt;em&gt;Gates of Repentance&lt;/em&gt;, the forthcoming new Reform High Holy Machzor, &lt;em&gt;Mishkan HaNefesh&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Gates of the Seasons&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Gates of the House&lt;/em&gt;, Josee Wolff and Marshall Portnoy&#039;s &lt;em&gt;The Art of Cantillation&lt;/em&gt;, and volumes of Reform responsa literature.&amp;nbsp; References to these sources are given in many Reform Luach entries for those who would like to explore a topic further.&amp;nbsp; Sources outside of Reform Judaism were also consulted in order to provide a traditional perspective in relevant places; these sources include the Koren-Sacks Siddur and Machzorim, Isaac Klein&#039;s &lt;em&gt;A Guide to Jewish Religious Practice&lt;/em&gt;, and the USCJ Luach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reform Luach is intended to assist Reform rabbis, cantors and prayer leaders in planning worship and synagogue observances.&amp;nbsp; Understanding that every synagogue&#039;s customs are different, Reform Luach offers suggestions for applying Reform siddurim, machzorim, and Torah commentaries to specific days in the Hebrew calendar.&amp;nbsp; Suggested liturgy generally reflects our Reform sources; in relevant places, you will also see notation that indicates traditional practice.&amp;nbsp; Torah and Haftarah selections reflect those indicated by the Plaut Torah commentaries; when Plaut&#039;s selections differ from traditional readings for a given day, both traditional readings and Plaut&#039;s suggested alternatives are listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key to the abbreviations used in the Luach:&lt;br /&gt;
	MT - &lt;em&gt;Mishkan T&#039;filah&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	P - Plaut Torah commentary&lt;br /&gt;
	RP - Revised Plaut Torah Commentary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WTC - &lt;i&gt;The Torah: A Women&#039;s Commentary&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JL - &lt;em&gt;Jewish Living&lt;/em&gt;, by Mark Washofsky&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ATC/AC - &lt;em&gt;The Art of Torah Cantillation&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Art of Cantillation, Vol. II&lt;/em&gt;, by Josee Wolff and Marshall Portnoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leon Morris, Executive Editor&lt;br /&gt;
	Amanda Kleinman, Managing Editor&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;em&gt;with special thanks to Michael J. Radwin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; and HebCal.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback, questions or suggestions?&amp;nbsp; Email us at ReformLuach@gmail.com&lt;/p&gt;
]]></content><private><![CDATA[]]></private><author><![CDATA[amanda]]></author></item>
