<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 22:50:54 -0400</pubDate><title><![CDATA[B&#039;dikat and Biur Chametz]]></title><url><![CDATA[b-dikat-chametz]]></url><meta><![CDATA[]]></meta><metad><![CDATA[]]></metad><menu><![CDATA[B&#039;dikat Chametz]]></menu><menuOrder><![CDATA[0]]></menuOrder><menuStatus><![CDATA[]]></menuStatus><template><![CDATA[template.php]]></template><parent><![CDATA[]]></parent><content><![CDATA[&lt;h3&gt;B&#039;dikat and Biur Chametz&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;General Notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evening before Pesach (or the Thursday night before Pesach when Pesach begins on Saturday night), we search for chametz in our homes as soon as possible after dark. We place pieces of chametz in different areas of our house, in order to ensure that there is some chametz to find during our search. We search darkened rooms by the light of a flashlight or candle. The procedure is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Recite the blessing before searching for chametz, which concludes with &quot;al biur chametz.&quot; (The full blessing can be found at the beginning of most Haggadot.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Collect the pieces of chametz you set aside, as well as any other chametz you find in the process of searching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Recite the formula by which you renounce ownership over any chametz you have inadvertently left in your house. (The formula begins with &quot;Kol chamira...&quot; and can be found at the beginning of most Haggadot.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Set aside the chametz you found during your search until the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. The following morning, before the time at which it becomes forbidden to eat chametz, we destroy the chametz that remains in our possession. Many destroy their chametz by burning it, though it is permissible to destroy or dispose of it in other ways (as long as it does not remain in your home). After destroying the chametz, we recite another passage renouncing ownership over any chametz that we have inadvertently kept in our homes (The formula begins &quot;kol chamira&quot; and can be found at the beginning of most Haggadot). &amp;nbsp;When Pesach begins on Saturday night, Biur Chametz is done on Friday without reciting this formula.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*When Pesach begins on Saturday night, make sure to leave enough chametz for Shabbat. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on B&#039;dikat and Biur Chametz, as well as on selling your chametz, see JL 101-102&lt;/p&gt;
]]></content><private><![CDATA[]]></private><author><![CDATA[amanda]]></author></item>
