<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 00:25:29 -0500</pubDate><title><![CDATA[Chanukah 4 Weekday]]></title><url><![CDATA[chanukah-4-weekday]]></url><meta><![CDATA[]]></meta><metad><![CDATA[]]></metad><menu><![CDATA[Chanukah 4 Weekday]]></menu><menuOrder><![CDATA[0]]></menuOrder><menuStatus><![CDATA[]]></menuStatus><template><![CDATA[template.php]]></template><parent><![CDATA[]]></parent><content><![CDATA[&lt;h3&gt;Chanukah (Day 4)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Shacharit&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the synagogue, light 4 Chanukah candles, without blessings, before Shacharit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add Al Hanisim for Chanukah (MT 556) to the Amidah (MT 95).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recite a full Hallel after the Amidah (MT 560). The Hallel on page 560 is the Half Hallel; congregations that would like to recite a full Hallel should add appropriate selections from Psalms 115 and 116.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Shacharit Torah Reading&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numbers 7:30-41 (P 1071, RP 931, WTC 831)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Aliyot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Mincha&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add Al Hanisim for Chanukah (MT 556) to the Amidah (MT 92)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Candlelighting&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light five candles after dark&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Place the Chanukiyah in a place where it will be visible from the outside. If lighting the candles in the synagogue, place along the southern wall of the synagogue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Place the appropriate number of candles into the chanukiyah. We begin with one candle on the first night and add another candle each night. We place the first candle on the right end of the chanukiyah, and add a candle to the left each night. We also prepare an additional candle, the shamash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light candles as soon after dark as possible. In the synagogue, light either before or after Ma&#039;ariv. First, light the shamash. Then, recite the two Chanukah candle blessings (MT 572). On the first night only, add Shehecheyanu. Then, light the Chanukah candles with the shamash, starting with the newest candle (furthest to the left).* While lighting the candles, or after lighting them, sing Hanerot Halalu (MT 572) and Maoz Tzur (MT 669).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candles should burn for at least half an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a custom to light Chanukah candles again, without blessings, before Shacharit in the synagogue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Friday, light Chanukah candles before lighting Shabbat candles.&amp;nbsp; On Motza&#039;ei Shabbat, light Chanukah candles before making Havdalah in the synagogue, and make Havdalah before lighting candles at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* A 1984 CCAR responsum discusses various traditions with respect to the sequence of lighting Chanukah candles. &amp;nbsp;The author suggests that, in the absence of a different family tradition, we should light from left to right in accordance with general Jewish practice. &amp;nbsp;For the full text of the responsum, see:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ccarnet.org/responsa/carr-278-279/&quot;&gt;http://ccarnet.org/responsa/carr-278-279/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ma&#039;ariv&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add Al Hanisim for Chanukah (MT 556) to the Amidah (MT 92)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Birkat Hamazon&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add Al Hanisim for Chanukah&lt;/p&gt;
]]></content><private><![CDATA[]]></private><author><![CDATA[amanda]]></author></item>
