<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 12:44:48 -0400</pubDate><title><![CDATA[Erev Purim]]></title><url><![CDATA[erev-purim]]></url><meta><![CDATA[]]></meta><metad><![CDATA[]]></metad><menu><![CDATA[Erev Purim]]></menu><menuOrder><![CDATA[0]]></menuOrder><menuStatus><![CDATA[]]></menuStatus><template><![CDATA[template.php]]></template><parent><![CDATA[]]></parent><content><![CDATA[&lt;h3&gt;Purim (begins at sundown)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;General Notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mitzvot of Purim:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a Mitzvah to hear the reading of Megillat Esther. The Megillah is traditionally read at both the evening and morning services.&amp;nbsp;On Purim, we give Mishloach Manot, gifts of food and drink to our family and friends. One should give at least two types of food to one person. &amp;nbsp;It is also a Mitzvah to give Matanot L&#039;Evyonim, gifts to the poor. We should give a gift to at least two people.&amp;nbsp;Finally, one should partake of a S&#039;udat Purim, a festive Purim meal in the afternoon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Procedure for Reading the Megillah&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. The reader should unroll the Megillah scroll and fold it like a letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. The reader recites the blessings before beginning to chant (MT 573).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. The reader then chants the Megillah, keeping in mind the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; a. Many communities have the custom to recite certain verses to special melodies. These verses and melodies vary &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;from community to community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; b. The following verses are chanted according to the trope for the book of Lamentations: 1:7, 2:6, 3:15, 4:1, 4:16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; c. Before the reader chants 2:5, 8:15, 8:16, and 10:3, the congregation should recite the verses. The reader should then continue with the chanting of the special verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; d. In 9:7, the names of Haman&#039;s sons are traditionally chanted quickly on one note, and in one breath, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; e. Whenever the reader chants Haman&#039;s name, the congregation makes noise in an effort to blot out his name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. The reader then chants the blessing after the Megillah. These blessings can be found in the Koren Siddur, pp. 903-904. Traditionally, this blessing is followed by the chanting of Shoshanat Ya&#039;akov. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &amp;nbsp;more information on reading Megillat Esther and examples of melodies see ATC II, 85 and A.W. Binder, Biblical Chant, Sacred Music Press, 1963.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ma&#039;ariv&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add Al Hanisim for Purim (MT 557) to the Amidah (MT 94)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the Megillah after the Amidah (for procedure, see above &quot;Reading the Megillah&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading the Megillah, continue with concluding prayers&lt;/p&gt;
]]></content><private><![CDATA[]]></private><author><![CDATA[amanda]]></author></item>
