<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 14:15:32 -0400</pubDate><title><![CDATA[Erev Rosh Hashanah Friday]]></title><url><![CDATA[erev-rosh-hashanah-friday]]></url><meta><![CDATA[]]></meta><metad><![CDATA[]]></metad><menu><![CDATA[Erev Rosh Hashanah Friday]]></menu><menuOrder><![CDATA[0]]></menuOrder><menuStatus><![CDATA[]]></menuStatus><template><![CDATA[template.php]]></template><parent><![CDATA[]]></parent><content><![CDATA[&lt;h3&gt;Erev Rosh Hashanah&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;General Notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is customary for synagogues to replace the Torah cover, Parochet (curtain covering the Ark), and cover of the reading table with white ones until after Yom Kippur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is &amp;nbsp;customary to visit the graves of loved ones on this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Shacharit&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not sound the shofar during Shacharit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclude the service with Acha Sha&#039;alti (MT 662).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Candlelighting&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light candles before sunset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recite the candle blessing for Shabbat and festivals, followed by Shehecheyanu (MT 384).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ma&#039;ariv&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recite an abbreviated Kabbalat Shabbat, consisting of Psalms 92 and 93, before Ma&#039;ariv. Some congregations also recite an abbreviated L&#039;cha Dodi before reciting Psalm 92.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Include other changes for Shabbat as indicated in the machzor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;During Dinner&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recite the Kiddush for Rosh Hashanah evening, with appropriate additions for Shabbat. Kiddush is followed by Shehecheyanu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before making HaMotzi, dip an apple in honey and recite the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Y&#039;hi ratzon mil&#039;fanecha, Adonai Eloheinu v&#039;Elohei avoteinu v&#039;imoteinu, she&#039;t&#039;chadeish aleinu shanah tova um&#039;tukah. May it be your will, Adonai our God and God of our ancestors, to renew us for a good and sweet year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, recite the blessing over fruit and eat the apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then make HaMotzi over two Challot. It is customary to eat round challot during this season. Some people sprinkle honey over their challah rather than salt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We add Ya&#039;aleh v&#039;Yavo and Harachaman for Rosh Hashanah to Birkat Hamazon.&lt;/p&gt;
]]></content><private><![CDATA[]]></private><author><![CDATA[leon]]></author></item>
