<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 18:06:43 -0500</pubDate><title><![CDATA[Hoshana Raba]]></title><url><![CDATA[hoshana-raba]]></url><meta><![CDATA[]]></meta><metad><![CDATA[]]></metad><menu><![CDATA[Hoshana Raba]]></menu><menuOrder><![CDATA[0]]></menuOrder><menuStatus><![CDATA[]]></menuStatus><template><![CDATA[template.php]]></template><parent><![CDATA[]]></parent><content><![CDATA[&lt;h3&gt;Sukkot (Chol Hamoed)&lt;br /&gt;
	Hoshana Raba&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;General Notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, Hoshanah Raba is considered to be the day of the final sealing of God&#039;s judgement. The liturgy for the day is an interesting mixture of weekday and festival liturgy, and we alternate between nusach for weekdays, festivals, S&#039;ichot, and the High Holy Days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Shacharit&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add Ya&#039;aleh v&#039;Yavo for Sukkot to the Amidah (MT 92).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perform N&#039;tilat Lulav after the Amidah (MT 571).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recite the full Hallel after the Amidah (560). The Hallel on page 560 is the Half Hallel; congregations that would like to recite a full Hallel should add appropriate selections from Psalms 115 and 116.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, after Hallel, the congregation would make 7 processions around the synagogue and recite seven Hoshanot. After the Hoshanot, the congregation would beat the Aravot against the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Shacharit Torah Reading - Traditional&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numbers 29:29-31 (P 1214, RP 1085, WTC 981)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 Aliyot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* Numbers 29:29-31 is read for each of the four aliyot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Shacharit Torah Reading - Alternative&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deuteronomy 11:10-15 (P 1407, RP 1239, WTC 1104)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;During Meals&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recite the blessing over dwelling in the sukkah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a mitzvah to welcome guests into our Sukkah. Each night of Sukkot, we symbolically welcome certain of our patriarchs and matriarchs into our sukkah as guests. The liturgy of this ceremony can be found in Gates of the House, pp. 77-78.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We add Ya&#039;aleh v&#039;Yavo and Harachaman for Sukkot to Birkat Hamazon.&lt;/p&gt;
]]></content><private><![CDATA[]]></private><author><![CDATA[amanda]]></author></item>
