<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 18:55:08 -0500</pubDate><title><![CDATA[Tisha B&#039;Av]]></title><url><![CDATA[tisha-b-av]]></url><meta><![CDATA[]]></meta><metad><![CDATA[]]></metad><menu><![CDATA[Tisha B&#039;Av]]></menu><menuOrder><![CDATA[0]]></menuOrder><menuStatus><![CDATA[]]></menuStatus><template><![CDATA[template.php]]></template><parent><![CDATA[]]></parent><content><![CDATA[&lt;h3&gt;Tisha b&#039;Av&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;General Notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tisha b&#039;Av commemorates many calamities that befell the Jewish people on this day, but it focuses on the destruction of the First and Second Temples. Reform Jews hold varying perspectives on this day, as many do not hope for the rebuilding of the Temple: some look upon the destruction of the Temples and the Jews&#039; expulsion from Israel as an opportunity to realize our mission to disseminate knowledge of God throughout the world; these people do not necessarily relate to Tisha b&#039;Av as a day of mourning. Others believe that, regardless of one&#039;s perspective on the destruction of the Temples and diaspora, Tisha b&#039;Av has resonance for us as a day to commemorate moments of sadness and tragedy for the Jewish people. For a more in depth discussion of Tisha b&#039;Av and Reform Judaism, see JL 129-130.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional prohibitions of Tisha B&#039;Av are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Eating and drinking&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sexual relations&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Bathing&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Using oils or lotions&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Wearing leather shoes&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Greeting one another&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Studying Jewish texts other than those in the mood of the day (such as Job and Lamentations).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Shacharit&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not wear a tallit or tefillin. After the Haftarah reading, recite Kinot. Some also chant Eicha, either after the Haftarah or at the end of the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Shacharit Torah Reading - Traditional&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deuteronomy 4:25-40 (P 1342, RP 1191, WTC 1069)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Aliyot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Shacharit Haftarah - Traditional&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeremiah 8:13-8:23 (P 1675, RP 1489)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Mincha&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is at this service that Tallit and Tefillin are worn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We add a Torah service (MT 104) after the Chatzi Kaddish (MT 57). The afternoon reading is the same as the morning reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the Torah reading, we read the Haftarah for public fast days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we recite the Amidah on fast days, we replace Shalom Rav with Sim&amp;nbsp;Shalom (MT 98).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Mincha Torah Reading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 32:11-14 (P 647, RP 588), 34:1-10 (P 658, RP 593, WTC 503)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Aliyot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Mincha Torah Notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a special custom regarding the chanting of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;32:12 (&quot;Shuv mei&#039;charon . . . l&#039;amecha&quot;)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;34:6-7 (&quot;Adonai Adonai . . . v&#039;nakei&quot;)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;34:9 (&quot;v&#039;salachta . . . u&#039;n&#039;chaltanu&quot;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the reader reaches these verses, the congregation recites the verses first. The reader then repeats them in High Holy Day cantillation. The rest of the portion is read in regular Torah cantillation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Mincha Haftarah Reading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah 55:6-56:8 (P 1681, RP 1489)&lt;/p&gt;
]]></content><private><![CDATA[]]></private><author><![CDATA[amanda]]></author></item>
