<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 00:16:42 -0500</pubDate><title><![CDATA[Tzom Gedaliah]]></title><url><![CDATA[tzom-gedaliah]]></url><meta><![CDATA[]]></meta><metad><![CDATA[]]></metad><menu><![CDATA[Tzom Gedaliah]]></menu><menuOrder><![CDATA[0]]></menuOrder><menuStatus><![CDATA[]]></menuStatus><template><![CDATA[template.php]]></template><parent><![CDATA[]]></parent><content><![CDATA[&lt;h3&gt;Tzom Gedaliah&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;General Notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzom Gedalyiah commemorates the assassination of Gedaliah ben Ahikam. After the Babylonians conquered Jerusalem and destroyed the First Temple in 586 BCE, King Nebuchadnezzar appointed Gedalyah as governor of Judah. Gedalyah&#039;s assassination a few months later marked the end of Jewish self-government in Jerusalem and the dispersion of the Jews remaining in Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a minor fast day. For those who chose to fast, the fast begins at sunrise and ends at sundown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many liberal Jews do not fast on the three minor fast days connected to the Temple, Shiva Asar b&#039;Tammuz, Asara b&#039;Tevet, and Tzom Gedaliah. Rabbi David Golinkin has written a responsum on this matter; he concludes that these three fast days should be considered optional, in recognition of the redemptive possibilities of the rebirth of the State of Israel. We should, however, fast on Tish&#039;a b&#039;Av, in order to acknowledge that we are still far from peace. See Golinkin, David. &quot;Should We Continue to Fast on Tisha B&#039;Av and the Other Three Fasts Which Commemorate the Destruction of the Temple?&quot; Responsa in a Moment 4, no.7 (2010). The full text of the responsum can be found at:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.schechter.edu/responsa.aspx?ID=53&quot;&gt;http://www.schechter.edu/responsa.aspx?ID=53&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Shacharit&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reciting every Kaddish, after the word &quot;l&#039;eilah,&quot; we add &quot;u&#039;l&#039;eilah.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reciting the Amidah, include passages marked, &quot;Between Rosh Hashanah and Yom Kippur&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We add a Torah service to Shacharit (MT 104). We chant the Torah reading for public fast days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclude the service with Achat Sha&#039;alti (MT 662)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Shacharit Torah Reading&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 32:11-14 (P 647, RP 588, WTC 503), 34:1-10 (P 658, RP 593, WTC 509)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Aliyot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Shacharit Torah Reading Notes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a special custom regarding the chanting of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 32:12 (&quot;Shuv mei&#039;charon . . . l&#039;amecha&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 34:6-7 (&quot;Adonai Adonai . . . v&#039;nakei&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;o&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 34:9 (&quot;v&#039;salachta . . . u&#039;n&#039;chaltanu&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the reader reaches these verses, the congregation recites them first. The reader then repeats them in High Holy Day cantillation. The rest of the portion is read in regular Torah cantillation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Mincha&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reciting every Kaddish, after the word &quot;l&#039;eilah,&quot; we add &quot;u&#039;l&#039;eilah.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Include a Torah service (MT 104) after the Chatzi Kaddish (MT 57). The afternoon reading is the same as the morning reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the Torah reading, we read the Haftarah for public fast days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reciting the Amidah, include passages marked, &quot;Between Rosh Hashanah and Yom Kippur.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we recite the Amidah on fast days, we replace Shalom Rav with Sim Shalom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Mincha Torah Reading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 32:11-14 (P 647, RP 588, WTC 503), 34:1-10 (P 658, RP 593, WTC 509)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Aliyot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Mincha Haftarah Reading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah 55:6-56:8 (P 1681, RP 1489)&lt;/p&gt;
]]></content><private><![CDATA[]]></private><author><![CDATA[amanda]]></author></item>
